# Rachel-Leanne Williams

Greater Sydney Area



rachel.williams@zaliet.com



02 8273 7510



linkedin.com/in/rachelleannewilliams

# Summary

Rachel leads a talented development team responsible for delivering Collaboration Software for law firms around the world. With over 10 years' experience delivering technology solutions and working inside law firms, she is passionate about helping law firms attract and better serve their clients online.

Recent innovations include the LEAP CRM and Web Portal, which facilitates online appointment scheduling and payment, secure document sharing and collaboration, and the ability to receive intake forms online, from any device.

Collaboration Software is part of LEAP Dev, an award-winning provider of firm management, lawyer/client collaboration, accounting and payment processing solutions to law firms around the world.

Learn more about LEAP Dev: https://leapdev.io/

## **Experience**



### Student

Coder Academy

Jan 2020 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

Diploma of Information Technology.

After 13 years in Legal IT i have decided to take the plunge and learn to become a full stack developer in 2020! I will continue to work part-time at LEAP Dev.

#### General Manager of Collaboration Software

**LEAP Dev** 

Jul 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months +)

Collaboration software is an integral evolution of legal practice management software. While practice management software helps law firms run more efficiently, collaboration software helps law firms work with clients online, at a time convenient to both parties.

At LEAP Dev, I work closely with our world-class developers to create collaboration software for law firms. Our innovations include our popular Web Portal - a single place where clients can communicate and collaborate with law firms, 24/7. Through a Web Portal, a law firm's clients can request appointments, complete intake forms, access their documents and pay their bills - securely on any device.

The Web Portal utilises a secure document sharing platform to allow clients and lawyers to collaborate on documents and use online intake forms. The Web Portal integrates with LEAP to reduce significant non-billable time and increase firm efficiency.

LEAP's collaboration software is designed to streamline a firm's non-billable tasks with it's unique CRM functionality, online appointment scheduling, document sharing tool and payment system.



#### Chief Executive Officer

Oct 2016 - Jan 2020 (3 years 4 months)

Zaliet has been helping law firms for more than 10 years and through extensive research and feedback from our clients, we have a deep understanding of how they work. We also have the ability to integrate online functions directly into LEAP, thereby enhancing your client experience.

A Web Portal is the one place where your clients can communicate and collaborate with your firm, 24/7. Your clients can find your phone number, access their documents, book appointments, and pay their bills - securely on any device.

Google has replaced the Yellow Pages so you need an easy place for people to find your phone number and make enquiries.

The Portal is the place.

Find out more at www.zaliet.com or direct message me rachel.williams@zaliet.com



#### Global Transitions Manager

LEAP Legal Software AU

Jul 2014 - Sep 2016 (2 years 3 months)

I am responsible for the operations and strategic development of LEAP data migration for clients, globally. There are five core areas of accountability in the role:

- Increase speed of client data migration, and intelligence of data mapping by developing innovative data migration solutions.
- Oversee quality assurance of department's data transition activity, particularly for trust accounting data.
- Develop, document and maintain global standards for data configuration, including internal systems.
- Manage projects to ensure that data is high quality, and teams are delivering on deadline.
- Establish and grow teams across multiple countries. (The Transitions team has quadrupled in size during my time in the role.)



### National Consulting Manager and Support Manager

LEAP Legal Software AU

Apr 2013 - Jul 2014 (1 year 4 months)

The dual responsibilities of this role drove business forecasting, and strengthened key stakeholder relations.

National Consulting Manager duties:

• Created and documented internal systems; including policies and procedures for consultants.

- Budgeted and forecast business requirements during period of growth and change.
- Mentored and developed team of state consulting mangers, to ensure that business growth was wellcoordinated.

Support Manger duties:

- Trained clients and consultants in best practise use of LEAP, to ensure that firms received full benefit of the product. Training formats included on-site mentoring, off-site group sessions, seminars and functions.
- Mentored and certified LEAP IT Partners to ensure they delivered impeccable client service and met revenue targets.
- Delivered operational efficiency by restructuring IT Partner program.



#### LEAP Cloud Products Manager

LEAP Legal Software AU

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013 (4 months)

- · Established an internal quality assurance department that contributed to product development.
- Facilitated product development by engaging clients and internal teams for testing and feedback.
- Resolved client enquiries that had been escalated from multiple arms of the business.
- Ran workshops ahead of product feature launches to ensure that internal teams were aligned on service and messaging. This helped teams deliver quality client service.
- · Managed integration opportunities and partnerships with third-party software providers.



#### NSW Consulting Manager

LEAP Legal Software AU

Mar 2012 - Dec 2012 (10 months)

- Managed client engagement across LEAP consultant teams; inclusive of installation and training.
- Documented internal policies, to ensure that clients received efficient and quality service.
- Organised 'user group' training and networking events to help clients better understand LEAP.

# A

# Implementation Consultant and Coordinator

LEAP Legal Software AU

Mar 2011 - Mar 2012 (1 year 1 month)

- Installed and configured LEAP, inclusive of client training.
- Applied in-depth knowledge of data configuration to the needs of small firms.

· Educated firms about LEAP solutions that boost productivity, profit, and accuracy of data management.

# National Help Desk Consultant

LEAP Legal Software AU

Mar 2010 - Mar 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Resolved client enquires and gain in-depth product knowledge.

#### Legal Secretary/Accounts

Anderson Boemi Lawyers

Dec 2008 - Mar 2010 (1 year 4 months)

Coordinated efficient workflow across firm, supporting lawyers specialising in conveyancing, criminal and family law.

This equipped me with insights on effective data management for a range of matter types and trust accounting.

#### **Education**



Gilroy Catholic College

2003 - 2008

Australian International School Singapore

2000 - 2002

🤊 Siebert Elementary School Midland, Michigan U.S

1994 - 1998

#### **Skills**

Cloud Computing • Management • Training • CRM • Leadership • Document Management • Team Leadership • Software Documentation • Customer Service • Business Planning